Florin Marius Drilea

5 - 15 Market Place, Sheffield Postal Code: S1 2GH

marius.drilea2016@gmail.com Phone: +447716312297florin-marius-drilea.netlify.app/

SUMMARY

PROFESSIONAL Reliable developer with a degree in Computer Science and background in different programming languages and Project Management activities. Hard-working and team working person with a lot of experience during my degree. I am also a qualified referee.

EDUCATION

University of Sheffield, South Yorkshire, England

July, 2020

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

- Web officer of Romanian Society
- Diploma of first place in EYH project
- Mentor at the University of Sheffield
- Student Ambassador
- Achieved 2.1

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Scala, Python, C#, C++, JavaScript, Ruby

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Couchbase, SQLite

Tools/Framework: Spring, Ruby on Rails, React, Hibernate, ActiveMQ, Kafka General: Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming, Machine Learning

EXPERIENCE

Sky Betting and Gaming - Software Engineer Oct. 2021 - Present

I worked in the promos team to develop new features and maintenance for our applications used in the Hub team. Working with Scala and Kafka to connect applications between them within our team and withing others using Jenkins to deploy our application in each environment and Kubernetes to manage our applications.

• Technology/Tools: Scala, Kafka, Jenkins, MacOS, Grafana, Kibana, Kubernetes, Docker, Testing

The Hut Group - Graduate Software Engineer

Feb. - Sep. 2021

Working in the supply and chain environment with microservices using agile methodology and programming in Java Spring Framework for the maintenance of the microservices and to develop new ones as well. Also worked in two different teams, one for finance integration and the other team for language connect. Some of my tasks included taking care of the infrastructure from my application and other applications that were created by our team.

• Technology/Tools: Java 11, RESTful Web Services, Jenkins, Microsoft SQL Server, Linux, Couchbase, PostgreSQL, Hibernate, Automation Testing

Crucible - Game Server Developer

Jul. - Sep. 2020

I worked as a java developer in this company in order to get the game engine and server developing of different types of slot games using a GDM game engine.

• Technology/Tools: Java 8, AWS, SQL

UniCredit Services - Junior Java Developer July 2019 - October 2019

I worked in an internship program at UniCredit Services, where we developed a project named TFO (Trade Finance). We worked in Java 8 and used different data sets to transfer the data from the reading of an OCR program to different locations.

• Technology/Tools: Java 8, JSON, SQL, RESTful Web Services

PROJECTS

Dissertation Project

2019 - 2020

Individual project in the data science field. The project is focused on analysing data and provide the best way for the placement of the air pollution sensors in Kampala, Uganda. For this I used machine learning techniques like Clustering methods and Gaussian Processes in order to find out which were the best features to be selected to do the final clustering approach in order to place the air pollution sensors using the best possible locations with the data sets that were used for this.

• Technology/Tools: Python, Machine Learning, Maths, Anaconda

Software Hut

October 2018 - June 2019

The project was a website that was keeping important data for a running club and has different automated features. I was assigned to do both front end and back end part in order to help both parts of the program to be well done. Most of my job was to connect the parts from the front end to the back end using the database created by us.

• Technology/Tools: Ruby on Rails, SQLite, Sass, Haml, JavaScript

Systems Design Group Project

Sep 2018 - Dec 2018

Worked in a 4 person team to develop a University Management System. We had to come up with a robust design that had to be represented using UML diagrams. Building a secure and efficient database was a major part of the design process. My main responsibility was the UML diagrams. I contributed to the database and helped with writing the java code.

- Technology/Tools: Java, Java Swing, JDBC, SQLite, UML Diagrams
- Link: github.com/FlorinMariusDrilea/University-System-Design-app

Optical Character Recognition

2018

I had to implement the classification stage of an optical character recognition (OCR) system for processing pages from a scanned book. The test data has been corrupted as well. The classifier should use a feature vector containing no more than 10 dimensions and should be able to operate robustly even on low quality image data. I considered using, LDA and PCA, but decided to implement LDA in the end. I implemented a vectorised k-nearest neighbours classifier which could classify the data in less time than other techniques.

- Technology/Tools: Python, Machine Learning, Clustering, Gaussian Processes
- Link: https://github.com/FlorinMariusDrilea/Optical-Character-Recognition

Software Engineering Group Project

2017 - 2018

Worked in a team of six people to develop a website that ordered pies with twitter using Twitter API. I was responsible for the user interface, but I took part in the development of all aspects of the software helping all the team members.

- Technology/Tools: Ruby, Sinatra, SQLite, Twitter API, HTML, CSS
- Link: github.com/FlorinMariusDrilea/Pie-project—Ruby

Java Chess Assignment

2017

This was one of my first big assignment that was done during university using object oriented programming and JAVA 8 in order to build up a chess game which was using artificial intelligence player as well. The interaction with the user can be either using the console from java, as a text display, or using a graphical user interface to move the pieces around. The option to play against a computer has two modes, which are easy and aggressive.

- Technology/Tools: Java 8, OOP
- Link: https://github.com/FlorinMariusDrilea/Chess-game-with-AI-

HackSheffield 3.0 October 2017

Worked in a team and built a project named S.S.Door, which had 2 features. The first was an alert system to prevent you from forgetting your keys. The second was a device that detects knocks on a door using a vibration sensor and then notifies the users. Our project won 3 prizes.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Languages

Romanian - Native; English - Fluent; Italian - Fluent; Spanish - Beginner Level;